The reason that the big accounts
are often broke is because they're big
accounts.
Let me explain this in a weird way. It
is almost impossible for
99% of people to get over a million
followers without becoming an entertainer,
without becoming someone
that tears down businesses, a
contrarian.
It is almost impossible to go above a
million followers without being
anti-establishment,
but also through gaming the algorithm.
Now, gaming the algorithm
is very difficult with just education,
and it's very
difficult with just problem-solving.
The character you need to become to be a
massive account is more
congruent with getting followers than it
is buyers.
We see these smaller accounts,
under 50,000 subscribers or under 50,000
Instagram followers,
they've never been tempted by that.
They've just honed in on getting an
audience of people that buy their stuff.
If you want a prime example of an audience
of followers, let's look at "Love
Island." You go on "Love Island" not for
people to buy your stuff, just purely an
audience.
You come off "Love Island," you have
millions of followers.
Yeah, they'll come to maybe a nightclub
if you're doing a PR event.
But the sponsorship deals you get
are indicative of how broke you are.
You don't really, I don't think,
get paid to go on "Love Island,"
and you just cash
out the deals you can get whilst you've
got your name in the limelight.
And then one of the probably exceptions to
the rule would be someone like Alex
Hormozi,
who has gained millions of followers just
through teaching people how
to sell.
You wouldn't see an Alex Hormozi video,
"This video is brought to you by
Squarespace." So the term we're going to
coin these people is giant
brokies,
because if you take their sponsors away,
they're broke.
There is no underlying business.
They have a follower-based economy, not a
client-based economy.